烧猪乐园：禽兽村【王少柱】制作
"Children care center"
（孤儿院）
"Tsai"
（奀仔)
ready... start!
准备，开始
39 seconds.
3 9秒
"Ar Dee"
（阿Dee)
ready... start!
准备，开始
Ready... start!
Ready and start!
准备，开始
What's mine is yours.
奀仔，我的就是你的
What's yours is mine. Here...
你的就是我的，拿！
Thanks!
多谢
Did you make that?
奀仔，你拼的？
Yes!
嗯
Hey, that's my candy!
喂，为什么抢我的糖
So?
不行啊？
Tsai! Help!
奀仔，救命呀
Help!
救命呀
Dee!
阿Dee
Tsai!
奀仔
Police! Out of the car!
警察，落车
A car hit the crowd at.noon today in downtown,
今日中午，在闹市发生私家车撞向人群
leaving 5 people dead and 18 injured.
至今已造成五死十八伤
The driver was miu kwok lung,
警方证实涉案司机
the ceo of a listed company.
为上市公司主席廖国能
Someone at the scene recorded
现场有市民拍到
miu crashed into the crowd at high speed
廖国能以高速撞向横过马路的途人
and stopped after hitting.a tour bus head-on.
之后再撞向迎头的旅游巴士才停下
Miu then used a cutter and killed himself
出事后，廖国能以一把界刀
by cutting his cervical aorta.
割向自已颈部大动脉自杀
He was pronounced dead on the scene.
其后证实死亡
A task force has been.set up to investigate.
警方已成立专案小组调查
The police allegedly got an anonymous tip
有消息指，事发前曾有匿名人士与警方联络
predicting the accident at the scene.
预告上址将有事发生
Since the accident earlier this month
今次是继本月初
involving a heavy goods vehicle in taipo,
「大埔重型货车撞人事件」之后
this is the second such.accident in a month.
第二宗严重车祸
The police received
两宗车祸同样有
an anonymous tip on both incidents.
匿名人士曾与警方联络
Hello, bill?
喂，阿Bill？
I just saw the news. You were right.
我刚刚看完新闻了，真的全被你猜中
If we could decode the file sooner,
如果可以早点破解档案的话
we could have minimized the casualties.
就不用死这么多人
What should we do with the data?
那老板，我们拿着这些数据
现在该怎么办？
I'll keep digging.
我要自已查下去
This is too big for us.
但这事太大了
We didn't hack into an ordinary database.
我们骇到的不是普通料
It's probably a secret service file.
可能是特工集团的料
Bill, keep the file safe.
Bill，保住档案
Hello?
喂?
Relax! I'm a cop!
别怕，我是警察
Stop the bus! Open the door!
停车，开门
Don't! There's a bomb.
有炸弹，不能停车
Control, where is ching to?
监控室，程滔位置？
No.25 bus on the eastern corridor.
程Sir在2S巴士上，上了东九龙走廊
Ok
好
Two suspicious vehicles are in pursuit.
有两辆可疑车辆追着目标
To, in position.
阿滔，到位
Jump!
跳过去
No!
不跳
Suspicious vehicles closing in.
可疑车辆从后方追上来了
Listen to me.
你听我说
On my count to three, let's jump.
我数一二三，我们一起跳出去
One.
一
You tricked me.
你玩我呀你
You said on your count to three!
不是说好一二三再跳吗？
You looked so cool when you jumped in.
你知不知你跳下来真的很有型
Could do better if you got me a chopper.
叫了你订架直升机，可以再有型点
Who do you think you are? Tom Cruise?
你以为你真的是汤告鲁斯？
What about you? Fukuyama masaharu?
你不也在装福山雅治吗？
Yiu ho yee, independent reporter?
姚可仪，独立记者？
That's just your cover.
记者只是你用来掩饰身份的
M.i.t. Grad.
你在美国麻省理工大学毕业
Electrical engineering and it major.
修读电机工程和讯科学系
Up-and-coming hacker,
亦是一名新冒起的知名骇客
who specializes in malware.
擅长编写恶意程式
You were arrested in the U.S. in 2016.
2016年，你被美国警方拘捕
But the NSA hired you instead
同年，美国国安局反征用你
and dropped all charges against you.
撤销对你的所有控罪
We found out prior to.the crash in downtown,
我们也查到，在闹市车撞人事件发生之前
in a café in wanchai,
你在湾仔一家咖啡店上网
you tipped off the police about the crash,
通知警方那里将会有事发生
despite being surrounded by cctv.
你明知那边有很多闭路电视还要这么做
That means you didn't want people to die.
即是你也不想看到有人死
If we're on the same side,
既然大家立场一致
why not work together?
为什么不合作？
Go ahead and detain me if you have proof.
如果你有证据扣留我的话，就扣留我
That won't be necessary.
那不用了
Sign your name and you're free to go.
你出去签个名便可以走
We'll tell the media you left the precinct.
警方会向各大传媒公布你离开警察局的消息
Someone just tried to kill me.
我刚刚才被人追杀
I'm dead if I walk out of here.
就这么走出去，我死定了
Probably just cripple you.
残废也有可能
These people have backing.
捉你的人来头也不小
Bodyguards won't help.
你请保镖也没有用
Good luck!
祝你好运
Sir!
阿Sir
About 2 weeks ago,
大约半个月前吧
I wanted to write about human trafficking
我想写一篇关于「人口贩运」的报导
I managed to
于是我用了我的方法
hack into an overseas database.
骇入了一个外国的大型数据库
Bill!
Bill！
But they caught on.
不料被对方发现了
We only managed to.download part of the file.
所以我只下载到他们的部份档案
They started their attack.
对方开始攻击我们
Our security system will.crash in 30 seconds.
防护系统30秒后失效
Most of those files were encrypted.
而这些档案大多数都有加密的
After we decoded them, we found out
破解了之后我便发现
someone intends to disrupt.taipo and downtown.
似乎是有人想在「大埔」和闹市
Someone intends to disrupt.taipo and downtown.
两个地方搞事情
I believe
我相信
the police is covering up for them.
他们这样做是有警察的包庇
What makes you say that?
你凭什么这样说？
Among the files I hacked into,
因为在我骇到的档案中
I found archive footages and texts.
我发现一条纪片，和一些文字资料
The texts were in english,
资料是用英文写成的
but incomplete like the archives.
和纪录片一样内容并不完整
I deduced from the texts,
但凭这些资料已经可以推断
there's an underground organization abroad.
外国存在一个地下集团
This organization kidnaps children
这个集团专门掳拐儿童
and trains them into field agents.
还长期训练他们成为特工
These agents have already
估计这些特工
infiltrated the police around the world.
已经大量渗透进了全世界的警队里
What's up?
怎么了，阿井？
The security wing will take over.
我们保安部会接手这案子
To, take a break.
阿滔，停一停
Grace, kill the mic.
Grace，熄咪
If sw wants us to hand over the case,
保安部想接手这宗案子
the acp should call us.
程序上，要助理处长通知我的
He's on his way.
助理处长快回来
Then let's wait till he's here.
要不等他到了再说
Excuse me, we need to continue.
不好意思，我们继续
No!
不行
She's involved in two major attacks.
她已经牵涉到两宗大型的袭击
This is definitely our case.
这案子，归我们管
Cheng,
阿井
the girl just started to talk.
这个女孩刚刚才开口说了两句
If you pull the plug now,
如果你现在喊停
everything will go down the drain.
我们会前功尽废的
Chong,
阿庄
pack up everything and.keep them under wraps.
把所有东西带走，确保要全部保密
Yes, sir!
收到
Sorry!
Sorry！
The girl mentioned dirty cops on the force.
那女孩刚才说警队里面渗入了很多黑警
I was thinking who should I guard against
我正在想我应该防范谁好呢？
and you waltzed in.
你就走进来了
Should I guard against you?
我是不是应该防范你呢？
Aren't you a cop?
你不也是警察？
Ching to, cib.
程滔，刑事情报科
6 years ago, he went undercover.
六年前当过卧底
归队后，办事常越界
Should I guard against him too?
我需不需要也防范他？
I won't dismiss your doubts.
我不否定你的怀疑
But who knows who's dirty?
但谁是黑警，有谁知道
Cheng sir!
井Sir
What did you tell her?
你跟她说什么？
By protocol, everything.related to the case,
根据警务程式，一切有关案情的资料
I can only report to my commanding officer.
我只能报告上级
Sw will take over the case.
保安部要接手这案子
We're waiting to hear from the acp.
我们正在等助理处长通知！
Yes, sir!
收到
You wore us out. We need a break.
被你弄得累死了，我们需要休息一下
Care for a late snack?
吃宵夜吗？
Don't forget what I said.
记住我说过的话
What did he say?
他说过什么了？
Nothing important.
没什么
Such an attitude.
这什么态度
You know about him and his poker face.
你第一天认识他？一向都板着个脸
Sw is a sensitive department.
而且现在转去了保安部，敏感部门
He's not entirely wrong.
没什么错
Still! You were his mentor.
是没错，但你也算他师父
Don't say that. That's ancient history.
这件事情你千万别再提了，很久以前的事情
He now holds a key position.
人家现在身居要职
Not me. I'm old school.
我不是的，我很老派思想的
Once a mentor, always a mentor.
我是一日为师，终身为父
Thank you.
谢谢
When you see me every day,
所以我希望你每天见到我
kneel, kowtow, serve me tea,
都给我倒杯茶，跪下，磕个响头
and address me as shifu.
喊声师父，我就满足了
Pour you a libation and burn incense too?
好，也奠酒，上香吧
What about the guy who.went after yiu ho yee?
想抓姚可仪的人，有什么特征？
He must have had military training.
看他的身手应该是受过专业的军事训练
Any update on the crash in downtown?
那「闹市车撞人案」有没有进展？
According to the assessment.of the task force
根据专责小组的判断
terrorists had the dirt on miu kwok lung.
廖国能可能有黑材料被疑似恐怖分子掌握
He did it to protect his family.
他为了保住家人，所以才犯案
Miu was in finance and loan.
廖国能的企业生意包括金融和借贷
His clients are mostly Europeans.
客户大多是欧洲人
After the incident,
这次出事之后
the stock price of his company
他公司连同他欧洲许多搭档
and his partners' companies took a dive.
的公司股票也全线下跌
Someone intends to use the attack
有人想利用袭击事件
to disrupt the economy.
影响金融经济
We should alert interpol.
我们要马上通知国际刑警
I suggest we contact the Myanmar police
我建议联络缅甸警方
to get the hard disk yiu ho yee mentioned,
把姚可仪提及的硬碟拿回来
because it contains deployment plans
因为里面的资料
of suspected terrorists
涉及到疑似恐怖分子所有的部署
that may endanger other countries.
也影响到其他国家的安全
I agree.
我同意
Me too.
我也同意
I'll contact the Myanmar police.
好，我联络缅甸警方
Cheng sir,
井Sir
put yiu ho yee in a safe house asap.
尽快安排安全屋给姚可仪
Yes, sir!
收到
Keep this case to yourselves.
这个案子，不可以再多一个知情人
No one else must know about it.
一个都不可以
Yes, sir!
收到
Hey!
喂
- About the case....- Tonight...
抢你的案子 今晚
Sorry, go ahead!
不好意思，你说
Sorry, I took your case.
抢你的案子，不好意思
Don't be silly. It's under your department.
别傻了，是归你部门管的
What were you saying?
刚才你想说什么？
It's not important. Here's the elevator.
没事，不重要，来，电梯到了
Happy birthday to you...
祝你生日快乐…
Wait! Make a wish!
等一下，先许愿
Think hard... it'll come true.
慢慢想，这样才会灵的
- Close your eyes..- Make a wish first.
闭上眼睛 许愿了再切蛋糕
The longer the better.
许得越长就越灵验
You're late.
你迟到了还搞事
Here's your present.
生日礼物
This piece of second-hand trash?
送我个二手破手表便当生日礼物
Some friend you are!
你可真够朋友
It took me all night to bid for it.
我在电脑前守了一夜才拍到的
Give it back if you don't want it.
你不要便还我
If I don't mind this crap, don't nag.
我不嫌弃你破手表，你就别啰嗦了
Why does an old man like kiddie stuff?
你都几十岁的人了
怎么还喜欢小孩子的东西
Everyone has a child inside. But not you.
这叫赤子之心，你没有
You won't understand.
你不会明白
I don't think you'd wear it.
我就不信你会戴着它
Of course not.
我确实不会戴
I'd keep it for 20 years and auction it.
我肯定是要收在床底下
二十年之后拿出来拍卖的
Cheng!
井
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
Thank you.
多谢
I meant to remind you in the elevator.
刚才在电梯前就想提醒你
No need. I remember.
不用提醒，我记得
Thank you
多谢
yip sir, let's take a picture.
叶Sir，过来拍张照
Ok...
好的
Let me just take one picture.
等我一下，先拍张照片
I have to go. Happy birthday.
不妨碍你，生日快乐，我先走了
You can't wait for me to take one picture?
拍张照都不等我？
When was the last time we had a drink?
我们俩多久没喝过酒？
"Hong Kong police force organisation chart"
（警队高层架构图）
The girl mentioned dirty cops on the force.
那女孩刚才说警队里面渗入了很多黑警
I was thinking who should I guard against
我正在想我应该防范谁好呢？
and you waltzed in.
你就走进来了
Should I guard against you?
我是不是应该防范你呢？
After we decoded them, we found out
破解之后我便发现
someone intends to disrupt.taipo and downtown.
似乎是有人想在「大埔」和闹市
Someone intends to disrupt.taipo and downtown.
两个地方搞事情
I believe the police is.covering up for them.
我相信，他们这样做是有警察的包庇
I deduced from the text,
但凭这些资料已经可以推断
there's an underground organization abroad.
外国存在一个地下集团
This organization kidnaps children
这个集团专门掳拐儿童
and trains them into field agents.
还长期训练他们成为特工
This organization kidnaps children
这个集团专门掳拐儿童
and trains them into field agents.
还长期训练他们成为特工
These agents have already
估计这些特工
infiltrated the police around the world.
已经大量渗透进了全世界的警队里
Ching-ching always loves.to eat ice cream every day.
晴晴常常放学都要吃冰淇淋
What do you think, sir?
我该怎么做，先生？
Morning!
早晨
Ching-ching, if you want ice cream,
晴晴，如果想吃冰淇淋
tell daddy, ok?
就告诉爸爸，知道吗？
Ok!
知道
What flavor do you like?
想吃什么味道？
Durian and chocolate.
我想吃榴槤，还有巧克力
You're so greedy.
那么贪心？
Bye, daddy!
再见，爸爸
Bye!
再见
Sir, you come back and have dinner tonight?
先生，你今晚会回来吃饭吗？
Cheng sir, I spoke to the Myanmar police.
井Sir，我和缅甸警方沟通好了
You leave for Myanmar in an hour.
一个小时后，你去缅甸参与行动
Bring back yiu ho yee's hacked files.
行动目标是将姚可仪骇到的档案资料拿回来
In case there's mole among us,
为了避免有内鬼
we should limit the people involved.
其实行动本来不适合太多人参与
But considering your backup,
但我考虑到支援的问题
I picked someone for you.
决定找几个人帮忙
I hope you won't object.
希望你没意见
I trust your arrangement.
我相信处长你的安排
Send them in.
带他们进来
Sir!
处长
Sir！
Cheng sir and ching sir go to Myanmar.
井Sir、程Sir，你们去缅甸
The local elite force will help you.
当地精锐部队会接应你们
Yip sir will hold down the fort at cib,
叶Sir坐镇刑事情报科
monitor the operation and provide backup.
除了监察行动，还要无间断支援他们
Yes, sir!
收到
Too low tech, right?
是不是挺低端的？
No, I played with it when I was little.
不是啊，我小时候也玩过
Everyone from our generation did.
我们这代人就是玩这些
Better than cell phones.
不用整天看着手机
I'm quite attached to it.
玩久了，还会有感情
Do you recognize me?
其实你认不认得我？
2 years ago in fanling,
两年前在粉岭的反恐训练
I was under you in an anti-terrorist drill.
我跟过你
I don't recall.
不认得
How unlike you.
不像你
Maybe it's an occupational hazard.
不过可能是我职业病
Cib's top criterion in.choosing an undercover
刑事情报科选卧底
is the ability to recognize a face.
的首要条件就是认人能力
I was a uc for several years.
我也当过几年卧底
You don't look like it.
你一点都不像
As a uc, you're too obvious.
我没见过卧底这么外露
The more you try to cover up,
越是假装掩饰
the easier it is to blow your cover.
但偏偏，便露出马脚
Obvious can be intentional.
外露也可以是故意的
Today, we have a joint operation
（缅甸语）今天我们和香港警方
with the Hong Kong police.
（缅甸语）展开联合行动
The objective is to safeguard
（缅甸语）目标是要保住港方
the evidence of their case
（缅甸语）一个涉案证据
and arrest all related suspects.
（缅甸语）还要搜捕一切嫌疑人
Intel shows target is in a crowded place.
（缅甸语）线报显示
（缅甸语）目标人物身处人口稠密的地方
In order not to alert the target,
（缅甸语）为免打草惊蛇
we'll go inside disguised as civilians.
（缅甸语）我们会以平民装束混入目标单位
If we encounter any attack or resistance,
（缅甸语）行动过程如果遇到任何突袭反抗
we swear to protect our.people against the enemy.
（缅甸语）我们誓必保卫人民性命
We swear to protect our.people against the enemy.
（缅甸语）对敌人勇抗到底
Yes, sir!
（缅甸语）遵命
North gate secure.
北面安全
Roger that!
收到
Keep quiet! Get out!
（缅甸语）安静，离开
Go...
（缅甸语）走！
Alpha team in position.
Alpha Team到位
Breaching in 3 seconds.
3秒后攻击
What's going on?
发生什么事？
No visual. No comms either.
没信号了，通讯器也没声音
To, do you copy?
阿滔，听到吗？
Men down. Send backup.
有人受伤，请增援
Cheng, talk to me!
阿井，说话！
Are we back up?
修复好了没有？
Hard disk...
硬碟
How much longer?
还要等多久
Still no visual.
画面还没修复好
Comms back up.
声音修复好了
To, do you copy? What's the status?
阿滔，听到了吗？现在什么情况？
Ambushed by an assassin.
有杀手伏击
We're in pursuit to retrieve the hard disk.
我们正在追那个杀手，要取回硬碟
Locate them.
定位他们的位置
Visual not steady.
画面还没能稳定
John, are you there yet?
阿庄，到了没有？
I have the hard disk.
拿到硬碟
B point!
B Point！
Reload!
换弹
Go!
走呀！
上！
Hop on! Landing!
你先上来，降落！
W ait for me!
等我！
I have the hard disk. They're not on board.
硬碟在我手，他们还没上机
They outgun us. Chopper is hit.
火力太猛，飞机快撑不住
Pending your order!
要求指令！
Yip sir!
叶Sir！
Pull out!
撤退
John, pull out.
阿庄，撤退
Pull out!
撤退呀！
Go!
走！
Yip sir, the hard disk is a blank.
叶Sir，硬碟里什么都没有
Ambush and cib comms went dead.
有人伏击，刑事情报科通讯系统出现问题
It's possible we have a mole.
很有可能，我们有内鬼
Regarding the operation,
对行动知情的人
15 people in the know, including us.
加上我们房里几位，总共十五人
What about yiu ho yee?
除此之外，大家有没有想过姚可仪这个人
Why didn't the assassin kill her
为什么杀手必要保住她的命
but want to kidnap her?
还要抓走她
If someone threatened miu kwok lung,
既然廖国能是被人要胁的
she might be threatened as well.
姚可仪也一样有可能被人要胁着
Is it possible yiu ho yee is a terrorist?
大胆推测，姚可仪有没有可能是恐怖分子？
Yip sir, what's your take?
叶Sir，你觉得呢？
Anything is possible.
我觉得一切也有可能
Does that include the missing ching to?
那包不包括还没有找到的程滔
Should we suspect him?
他也值得被怀疑？
Myanmar police cleared the scene.
缅甸已经清理现场
But still no sign of him.
但是仍然找不到他
The point is,
最重要的是
he was the last person.to touch the hard disk
他最后接触过那硬碟
I'm afraid I can't keep up.
我想我跟不上大家的节奏
While I worry about my colleague's safety,
我还在担心我伙计的安危
you're questioning his loyalty.
但你们却怀疑他是不是有问题
You don't give a damn about his safety,
我真的不明白一个人的性命安危你们不管
because you're anxious to get answers?
是不是因为你们急着为这件事情找个解释？
Maybe I dropped the ball.
当是我失职吧
Ching to worked for me for a long time.
程滔跟了我很多年
He's my buddy.
是我的好兄弟
I will not suspect him.
我不会怀疑他
What if I told you
那如果我告诉你
I have intel
有情报显示
ching to is on the take?
程滔有可能是黑警呢？
I can vouch for him.
我担保他
Safe house!
去安全屋
Yes, sir!
收到
Hold it!
站住！
What now?
干什么？
Any word on to?
阿滔现在有什么消息？
Pending the Myanmar police's report.
缅甸警方在调查，我也在等报告
- You came back with John..- Didn't I make myself clear?
你跟阿庄一起回来 我说得够清楚吗？
Why didn't anyone stay behind to find out?
为什么你不留一个人等消息呀？
It's a human life.
是人命来的
So you noticed?
你也知道是人命？
Then why did you order them to pull out?
那你下令撤退？
To disappeared
阿滔的失踪
because of you.
是你间接造成的
I must find him.
我一定要找回他
I will let them know
我要让那帮家伙知道
he's not a dirty cop.
他不是黑警
He came back for me.
阿滔有回头救我
He can't be dirty.
他怎会是黑警
It's useless for me to stay in Myanmar.
我留在缅甸是没用的
Yiu ho yee is our only lead.
现在唯一的线索，就是姚可仪
Trust me.
相信我
Sorry!
对不起
I'm sorry!
Cheng sir is here.
井Sir到了
Why is the hard disk a blank?
为什么那硬碟是空的？
Did you make it up?
是不是所有事都是你编出来？
What do you mean?
你说什么？
There were heavy casualties in Myanmar.
我们在缅甸死了很多人
Start telling us the truth.
你还不说真话？
What about bill?
阿Bill呢？
Dead.
死了
Who are you?
你到底是什么人
What's your connection with the terrorists?
跟恐怖分子有什么关系？
You want to bury Hong Kong with you?
你是不是要全香港的人跟你一起陪葬
Bill is dead.
阿Bill死了
I won't say another word.
我什么都不会再说
On account of your.possible false statement,
现在我怀疑你给假口供
and connection to two terrorist attacks,
加上跟两宗恐怖袭击案有关
you're now under arrest.
所以正式拘捕你
Yes, the hacked files
没错，那个被走的档案
will be treated as a permanent leak.
要视为永久泄漏
Our Hong Kong agent has.confirmed the hacker
但是我香港的特工已经确定
knew nothing about our list of agents,
那个骇客对我们特工的名单一无所知
and is clueless about details and timeline
对我们全球行动的细节和时间表
of our global operation.
只是掌握有限
The hacker has shut down.the entire data system.
但是骇客锁住了我们的资料系统
We won't be able to execute any plan
只要系统一天打不开
unless the system is unlocked.
我们都实行不了任何计划
All of our efforts over the years
总部多年来的心血
will just go down the drain.
会毁于一旦
Tung, you should really know,
董，你应该非常清楚
the aftermath of this.will indeed be terrible
如果这件事不妥当处理的话
if this incident is not.reversed immediately.
后果将会有多可怕
Grasp your time.
把握时间
Mr. tung, hq has reverted.
董先生，总部回复
They still can't unlock the files.
用尽所有方法也无法解锁
We must find the hacker.
一定要抓到那个骇客
Did we get what I want in Myanmar?
缅甸行动，能不能拿到我想要的东西？
I have the hard disk.
那硬碟在我手
Car 1, in 400m reroute to...
头车，4 0 0米后改道去
Get down!
趴下
Why you?
为什么会是你
What do you want?
你想怎么样？
I didn't really know at first.
之前我自己也不知道
I'm actually
其实我是一个
a greedy and righteous cop.
既贪钱，又正义的警察
It's so bloody contradictory.
很矛盾，想不通
Until yiu ho yee gave me the answer.
幸好，直至姚可仪的出现我终于找到答案
I haven't been a sell-out yet
不出卖正义
because the price was not right.
也只不过是价钱未够
你不要跟我说废话
You have yiu ho yee,
姚可仪在你手上
hand her over.
交她出来
I just told you, I chose money.
我刚才不是跟你说过，我选择了钱
You know how much she's.worth on the market.
那女人现在在人质市场值多少钱，你知道的
I'm giving you a chance to work with me.
我给你一个机会跟我合作
I can plead your case in the future.
将来我还可以帮你求情
I recorded this just now.
这影片是我刚才拍到的
You were next to your.aide when he was shot.
你助手中枪的时候你在他身边
Why did the gunners shoot.at him and not you?
为什么枪手只打他不打你？
Is it possible
会不会那些人
you sent those thugs?
是你派来的？
Quit your good cop act.
还装好警察？
Aren't you tired?
你累不累呀？
Tsai!
奀仔
Blanks?
空弹？
You're tsai?
你是奀仔？
Emma, does ching-ching.still have the fever?
Emma，怎样？晴晴退烧了没有？
Better. I think it's the water.
好点了，我想她不适应这里的水
Why did we move here?
其实为什么我们要搬来这里？
She can't adapt.
BB很难适应的
Honey, anyway, I'll support.whatever reason it is.
老公，不管什么原因，我也会支持你的
We'll talk when you get home.
好啦，等你回来再商量
Emma?
Emma？
Poor baby.
这么凄凉
Don't cry.
不要哭了
We're not against having a family.
总部不是不让你结婚生小孩
But you can't turn your back and walk away.
但是你不能违反制度一走了之吧
Take your pick.
两个你选一个吧
Mr. tung,
董先生
I won't do it again.
我以后不敢
Emma!
Emma
We taught you
总部教过你
people you love will suffer.
你有关心的人结果会更惨
See?
你看到了吧！
Honey!
老婆
5 more years.
再过五年吧
We'll let you go in 5 years.
五年后，总部会给你自由
You drew a good lot. You're with Cheng sir.
你今天分组抽到支好签喔，跟井Sir
Really?
是吗？
We taught you
总部教过你
people you love will suffer. See?
你有关心的人结果会更惨，你看到了吧！
Do you recognize me?
其实你认不认得我？
2 years ago in fanling,
两年前在粉岭的反恐训练
I was under you in an anti-terrorist drill.
我跟过你
I don't recall.
不认得
Dee!
阿Dee
Tsai!
奀仔
Drink some water.
喝口水
Just kill me. Don't waste your time.
你要杀就杀，别浪费时间
In 2013,
2013年
you became an independent reporter,
你成为独立记者
and went to the Philippines
去了菲律宾的红灯区
to cover the red light district.
做深度采访
You were there for 3 years.
一去，便去了三年
In 2017,
2017年
you fell off the grid
你在整个新闻圈内消失
and became active only recently.
直至最近才活跃起来
You disappeared because of her.
你消失的原因，是因为她
An m.I.T. Honor student became a reporter
一个麻省理工的高材生去当记者
because you needed an excuse
是想借着记者的背景
to look for someone in unusual places.
去一些特殊的地方找人
Unfortunately,
很可惜
by the time you found her,
当你找到你想找的人的时候
she was already dead.
她已经不幸离世
Why did you dig that up?
你为什么要把她给搜出来？
My little sister died tragically.
我妹妹死得很惨
It was horrible.
她死得很惨
You grabbed her.
就是你们把我妹妹抓走
When she ran away from the camp,
她从营里逃走出来的时候
you sent her to a brothel.
你们送她去卖淫
She was only 8 years old!
她才八岁呀
Why didn't you just kill her?
为什么你们不直接杀死她
Even if you kill me, I.won't unlock the files
就算你杀了我，我也不会帮你们解锁的
ching to is not the bad guy.
程滔他不是坏人
He's been acting on my orders.
他一直都在听我的命令做事
In order to secure your.hard disk in Myanmar,
在缅甸为了保住你的硬碟
he had to disappear.
所以他假装失踪
I have the hard disk.
拿到硬碟
那硬碟在我手
Good job.
做得好
He took you here on my order to protect you
他抓你来这里，也是听我命令要保护你
He's part of a counter terrorist ghost team
他其实是隶属香港警队一个专门
under the Hong Kong police.
打击恐怖分子的神秘部队
Iff, the invisible frontline force.
IFF，隐形战线部队
Because the iff is highly confidential,
因为要高度保密，所以隐形战线部队
it is outside the establishment,
是在警队常规编制以外
and they report directly to me.
他们是直接向我报告
If it's highly confidential,
既然要高度保密
why are you telling me?
那为什么要告诉我？
I want you to help us fight terrorists.
我想请你一起打击恐怖分子
I want to know why they.wish to capture you.
我想知道他们一直要抓你的原因
Because I locked their data system.
因为我锁住了他们的电脑系统
I didn't have time to download everything.
当时，我不够时间下载所有档案
But it dawned on me
所以灵机一触
to send them a virus
我向他们发送了个病毒
to paralyze their system,
病毒的功能就是瘫痪他们的电脑系统
stop them from operating it
并且不能再进行任何操作
and deny them access to their database.
也就是说
And deny them access to their database.
他们再打不开他们资料中心的任何内容
The only way to unlock it,
而唯一解锁的方法
is my Iris.
就是我的虹膜
We're currently outside the home of
我们现在身处的位置
missing sp of police, Cheng chun yin.
就是失踪警司井进贤的家外
The police is inside combing for evidence.
里面有大批探员仍然在搜证
Regarding the kidnapping of yiu ho yee
至于怀疑被人拐走
the key witness to the crash in downtown...
车撞人案的关键证人姚可仪，警方现正…
Relax! Your daughter is safe with us.
放心，我们已经接到你的女儿了
Thank you so much.
谢谢
Did you know someone
知不知道有人放风说
is looking for a buyer for yiu ho yee?
姚可仪在他手上，想找买家？
I didn't know.
不知道
They also claim to have the hard disk.
连那个硬碟也在他们手上
Who is it?
什么人？
Probably the missing cop from Myanmar.
我们估计那个是在缅甸失踪的警察
Your old partner.
即是你的老搭档
He's with cib. He's not my partner.
他是刑事情报科的人，不是我老搭档
Find out where he stands.
摸清楚他的底细
Set up a meeting with him in your name.
用你的身份，把他约出来
I see.
明白
Wait to hear from me.
等我的消息吧
"03:00 cheung sha wan cooked food market"
when Cheng escaped through the window,
井进贤穿窗逃走
he left behind a blood sample.
留下的血液样本
Based on his DNA
经过DNA鉴定
we confirm he's your childhood friend tsai.
证实井进贤，就是你小时候的朋友，奀仔
What's mine is yours.
奀仔，我的就是你的
What's yours is mine.
你的就是我的
Over the years, while.looking for you friend,
这么多年以来
over the years, while.looking for you friend,
你一直查探你失踪朋友的消
you have been feeding us intel
不断提供
about this secret organization.
神秘集团的情报给我们
Why?
为什么？
I'm sure they kidnapped my friend.
我敢肯定，我朋友当年就是被神秘集团掳走
He's innocent.
他是无辜的
If he didn't come back.to save me back then,
如果小时候不是因为他救了我
I would have been the bad guy.
今天的我，就是贼
Sir!
Sir！
Here's your chance.
今天你终于等到一个机会
We intend to set up a new task force,
警队准备成立一个新的部队
that may help you find your friend.
希望你透过这里，可以找回你的朋友
Sir, strictly speaking, he's a victim.
Sir，严格来说，他也是受害人
Can I speak to him before the operation?
可不可以在行动之前，让我跟他说几句？
Back then, he might have been a victim.
他小时候的确是受害人
But today,
但是时至今日
you have no idea what he has become.
你已经没办法估计他变成什么样
If you're soft with him,.will he reciprocate?
你对他心软，他会不会也是一样？
Sir, he must have his reasons.
Sir，我觉得他是有苦衷
He took bullets for me in Myanmar.
在缅甸他帮我挡过枪
The other day when he fired those shots,
还有，他向我开那两枪
he aimed to miss.
都是故意射失
He didn't know they were blanks.
他不知道是空弹
I think he never intended to kill me.
我觉得，他根本就没有想过要杀我
Ok!
好
5 minutes.
五分钟
Leung sir will breach in 5 minutes.
五分钟之后，梁Sir就会带队攻进去
Yes, sir! Thank you, sir!
收到！ 谢谢！
Follow your orders.
记住听指令
Do you still play this?
还有没有玩这个？
Yiu ho yee, the hard disk. Name your price.
姚可仪，硬碟，开个价
When we were little,
我记得小时候
inside the orphanage,
我跟你在孤儿院
we were great with the rubik's cube.
玩扭计骰很棒
We were naughty and the teachers hated us.
也很调皮，老师都很讨厌我们
But they also knew we were smart.
但是知道我们很聪明
It drove them crazy.
害他们经常很矛盾
Don't try my Patience.
我没什么耐性
This is your file.
这是你小时候的档案
We have been apart for so long,
其实我跟你分开这么多年
many things have become fuzzy.
很多事我已经很模糊
I only remember
我只记得
the way you laughed when you were happy.
你开心笑的时候的样子
He's an old friend?!
原来是你老朋友
Sounds like he wants to catch up.
听语气，他挺想跟你叙旧
First you tell me you want money.
你一时又说钱可靠
Now you talk about the good ole' days.
现在又跟我玩叙旧
Make up your mind.
你想清楚再跟我说
We're running out of time.
没时间了
Tsai, let me help you.
奀仔，给我个机会帮你
Name your price.
开价
Ching sir, your boss from cib is here.
程Sir，你刑事情报科的长官来了
"Private number"
"I am ching sir's snitch."
"03:00 cheung sha wan cooked food market"
I'm so happy to see you both.
看到你们两个出现我真的很开心
To, I thought I got you killed.
我还日日夜夜以为我害了你，滔
Seeing you alive and in one piece,
看到你齐齐整整完好无缺
I'm so relieved.
我真的放心
And you, Cheng!
怎么了，阿井？
I thought you were kidnapped by terrorists.
害我还担心你被恐怖分子抓了
When in fact you had a date.
原来你们两个自己约见面
Care to share this happy occasion with me?
怎样？这么开心的事
有什么可以分享一下？
I will tell you what you want to know.
你想知道的事我会回答你
But right now, you need to leave.
但你要先走
You said I'm your shifu, right?
你口口声声叫我做师父，对吧？
But your snitch knows more than I do.
现在你的线人知道的事情比我还多
Should I answer you when you call me shifu?
你以后叫我师父，我该不该回应你？
Cheng, do you know what people said
阿井，你知不知有很多人
about you behind your back?
在你背后跟我说了你很多事
But you still have my vote.
但我一样这么信任你
You think I suspect you both?
你们猜我有没有怀疑过你们两个？
No!
没有
The answer is no!
是没有
Because I trained both of you.
因为你们两个是我教出来的
If I had doubts about either of you,
如果连你们两个都怀疑
then I must be a complete failure.
我觉得我做人会很失败
But the fact is,
但是事实证明
I am a failure.
我真的很失败
Suspicious character at exit a.
A出口有可疑人物
3 more at exit c.
C出口有三个可疑身影
All teams regroup.
大队准备
If you have nothing to say,
如果大家没什么说的
call the boys
便叫人把兄弟们约出来
and we'll celebrate.
给你们洗尘庆祝一下
No thanks.
不用
You should leave.
你走
I told you to leave!
我叫你走啊
Time to say goodbye.
是时候送他上路了
Make ching to kill him.
叫姓程的杀了他
Kill him!
杀了他
Are you nuts?
你疯了？
Tell him you'll trade if he takes him out.
告诉他，如果他敢动手，随时跟他交易
Go!
上
Put pressure on it.
按着它
Press!
按着它啊
Is this an operation?
你是不是在行动？
Yes!
是！
This is an operation.
我是在行动
They want the swap in Spain.
现在歹徒要求在西班牙进行交易
Ching sir will pose as the seller
程Sir会以卖家的身份
and hand over yiu ho yee.
交出姚可仪
The local g.E.O. Will back us up.
当地的反恐特别行动小组将会支援我们
We'll split into 3 teams.
我们会分成三组人
A team, ching sir, Johnson and chi...
第一组，会是程Sir、Johnson还有阿超
B team, assault team and sniper team.
第二组，会是攻击队还有狙击手队
C team, tech support and bg team.
第三组，会是技术支援队还有掩护队
Leung sir, last night at 19:00,
梁Sir，于昨晚时间1 9点
the nanny and Cheng chun yin's daughter
那保姆抱了井进贤女儿
left the flat with two men.
跟着两名男子离开
She's probably still in Hong Kong.
应该仍然在香港的
Keep looking. I need an exact location.
继续找，我要正确位置
Yes, sir!
收到
It's Mr. tung.
董先生
Yes?
是
We still don't know ching to's motive,
虽然还没有弄清楚程滔的动机
but I think he's tied.to the Hong Kong police
但是我觉得他应该跟香港警队仍然有关连
don't underestimate him.
所以你们绝对不能轻敌
Yes.
是
Mr. tung!
董生
Yes?
说
It has been 5 years.
也已经五年
When can I leave with my daughter?
我跟我女儿什么时候可以走？
The nerve of you to bring that up!
你还有胆量提出来
We made you an sp
我们帮你弄到警司的位置上
and invested so much resources in you.
花了这么多心血在你身上
What have you done for us?
这么长时间以来，你贡献过什么？
Now you even blew your cover.
现在弄到连身份也暴露了
We still won't give up on you,
总部也没有考虑过放弃你
but will help you start over.
还帮你重新来过
Have you considered how much
可你有想过
time and resources were wasted on you?
这会浪费总部，多少的资源和时间？
Never bring up leaving again.
你懂的，以后不要再提走这个字了
Do you and your daughter
你们父女俩
want the gifts we have given you?
还要不要总部给的恩赐？
Yes!
要
Very good!
那就好
This specialty from the Philippines,
菲律宾特产
is part of my childhood memory.
是我的童年回忆
Have a candy. Sugar can help you relax.
吃颗糖吧，糖份可以使人放松
Thanks for risking your life to help us.
多谢你这一次愿意冒险帮我们
I should say,
应该是说
I have waited too long for this.
我等这天等了很久
If you have doubts,
如果你有犹豫
it's not too late to say no.
现在反悔还来得及
Don't worry,
放心吧
my sister will be watching over me.
我相信我妹妹一定会保佑我
I'm well prepared for this.
我已做好心理准备
Mr. tung, we've got the location.
董先生，找到他们的位置
Target's locked.
目标锁定
C team, ready?
C Team，准备好了吗？
In position.
到了！
Ok, wait for your order over there.
好，在那边等通知
Ching sir, 9 o'clock.
程Sir，9点方向
5 o'clock.
5点方向
Two targets at 3 o'clock.
两个目标3点方向
10 o'clock.
10点方向
Mr. tung, he's here.
董先生，他到了
Any minute now.
随时开始
I'll give you half the money.
我先给你一半钱
You killed my buddy.
你们杀了我好朋友
That made me very upset.
让我很不开心
It's now a different deal.
所以现在协议改了
Your life is part of the package.
要加上你的命
Sorry!
对不起
I can't help you.
我无能为力
Demon, give him the other phone.
Demon，把另外一部电话交给他
Talk to me.
说
You have no right to settle the score.
你有什么资格跟我的人算账？
I don't? I'll drop the phone now,
我没资格？我现在就扔下电话
and talk to you after I ride on a bull.
拉一头牛过来骑，骑完再跟你谈也可以
You want to play games?
跟我玩？好
I'm happy to oblige.
那我也跟你玩一下
If you don't hand over yiu ho yee, fine!
你不把姚可仪交出来，没问题
I'll make Hong Kong foot the bill.
我就找香港人算账
I'm partial to deadly games.
我最喜欢便是玩死亡游戏
Apart from this one, there are three more.
除了这个，还有三个
All set to go off during rush hour.
会在下班的繁忙时间
Boom! Boom! Boom!
一起爆炸，崩
If you don't work for the Hong Kong police,
怎么样？如果你不是代表香港警察的话
you don't give a damn.
应该对你没什么影响
Looks like you have tricks up your sleeves.
看来，你好像还有很多把戏
Yes, I can call off the trade.
没错，我可以宣布交易取消
Demon, Cheng, leave!
Demon、阿井，走
Fine! You better not grovel on your knees.
好啊，等一下，不要向我下跪
You think you can pull a.fast one in the tunnel?
你以为你在隧道里换人神不知鬼不觉？
You can't fool me.
你骗不了我
Target's locked.
目标锁定
You have no bargaining chip.
你根本没有资格跟我谈交易
I solved all the problems.
因为凭我的本事，已经解决所有的问题
System unlocked. Restoring.
成功解锁，系统修复中
If you wish to kneel, there's still time.
如果想给我下跪的话，现在还来得及
Restoring failed.
修复失败
Someone is hacking in at ultra high speed.
系统再次被高速入侵
Exit point at your 12 o'clock, 800m away.
撤离地点在你12点方向，800米以外
You wanted to call it off.
又是你说要取消交易的
Now you want to continue?
现在又想继续啊？
You think you have the real yiu ho yee?
你以为姚可仪真的被你掳走了？
C team, ready?
C Team，准备好了吗？
In position.
到了
Ok, wait for your order over there.
好，在那边等通知
Roger.
收到
The real one is viewing your secrets.
真的姚可仪正在参观你的秘密
Didn't you notice a blip on your monitors?
你没发现刚刚你的电脑画面被扰了？
During the blip,
其实在那个时候
we inserted a pre-recorded visual.
已经换上我们预先拍摄好的画面
You thugs are too dead to play the endgame.
我想你的杀手们，应该没命玩压轴游戏
Still don't get it?
还不明白？
The Iris scan didn't unlock anything.
就是当你以为收到虹膜解锁的时候
It's in fact, another virus.
其实，只是另一种的电脑病毒
Kill the girl!
杀了那女的！
Ching sir, I found the bombs.
程Sir，我知道那三个炸的位置
I can track them to their base.
我有机会追踪到他们基地的位置
Armor integrity 15%. Evacuate...
防护数值15%，撤离，撤离
Go!
走啊！
走
Run, ho yee! Go!
走吧，可仪，走！
Sis, help me!
妹妹，保佑我
Armor integrity 5%. Evacuate...
防护数值5%，撤离，撤离
Armor integrity 3%. Evacuate...
防护数值3%，撤离，撤离
Their base is not in Spain.
他们的基地不在西班牙
It's in Hong Kong...!
在香港！
Call ctru!
马上通知反恐特勤队
Armor integrity 1%. Evacuate...
防护数值1%，撤离，撤离
Police! Freeze!
警察，站住，站住！
There's a bomb! Clear out!
有炸弹，全部人离开，走！
Demon, Cheng!
Demon，阿井
Kill that cop!
杀了那警察！
W-a-l-l
墙壁
（救我女儿）
Reload!
换弹
Go!
走！
Destroy the system.
销毁系统
Your daughter is safe.
你女儿很安全
Don't be afraid. I'm a policeman..Come here.
妹妹不用怕，我是警察，跟我来
After all these years,
这么多年来
this is the only thing I can do for you.
我只能为你做到这件事
For 30 years, you took the heat for me.
但你替我熬了三十年
If you hadn't come back for me,
如果当初不是你回来救我
the one they have taken
被人绑走的
should have been me.
是我才对
All these years...
这么多年来
How could you stand it?
你是怎么过？
How could you?
你是怎样过的？
Dee,
阿Dee
it's ok.
没关系
It's over.
过去了
It's ok.
没关系
We're brothers.
做兄弟
Whatever I still owe you,
这辈子还不完给你
in the next life...
下辈子我…
Come on... didn't you.want to save your pal?
过来呀，你不是要救你兄弟吗？
Dee,
阿Dee
see you around.
下辈子见
Let go!
放手！
"The loner dwells on memories"
「孤独的人 在回忆里入座」
"drifting around like a segment of a story"
「沿途漂泊 像故事的段落」
"a promise concealed in time"
「某一句誓言 被时光藏匿了」
"condensed into Amber after many years"
「多年后凝结 成琥珀」
3 months ago, in Spain and the Philippines
三个月前，国际刑警分别在西班牙及菲律宾
interpol busted many child soldier camps.
捣破多个童兵训练营
Children rescued from these camps
被救出的儿童目前被安置于
have been moved to local orphanages.
当地的临时孤儿院
"One must pay one's debt"
「人失去的 当欠了该还的」
"may those apart find what they want."
「愿失散的 旧爱各得其所」
"I loved regrets, I have no regrets."
「我爱过遗憾 此生才无憾了」
"The longing I have is silent"
「赠你的挂念 是沉默」
"ll hope we don't have to ask why"
「但愿你我 别再问为什么」
"who knows why things come and go"
「风吹云散来得也去得 谁参得透因果」
"ll hope we can be happy"
「但愿你我 能如约的快乐」
"so we won't waste our encounter"
「才不辜负 相遇多难得」
"time is like a train,.we're like passengers.”
「时光好似列车 我们都是旅客」
"The most beautiful part.is we were together."
「最美不过 同行过」